(this.webpackJsonpenglish=this.webpackJsonpenglish||[]).push([[0],{121:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"passage":["My name is Petty and this is my husband, Phil. We both work in an office in London. We have breakfast at half past seven. We don\'t have a big breakfast. We usually have bread, coffee and orange juice.","For lunch, we usually have salad and sandwich. That\'s at about 1.30.","We usually have dinner at half past seven in the evening. It is a big meal of the day and we have meat or fish with vegetables and potatoes or rice. We have orange juice. On Saturday evenings we go to a restaurant for dinner at about eight o\'clock."],"questions":[{"question":"Petty and her husband work in a(n)____","A":"office","B":"factory","C":"hospital","D":"clinic","answer":"office"},{"question":"What do they usually have for breakfast?","A":"soup","B":"butter","C":"bread","D":"fish","answer":"bread"},{"question":"What do they have for lunch?","A":"soup and fish","B":"salad and soup","C":"salad and sandwich","D":"sandwich and fish","answer":"salad and sandwich"},{"question":"What time do they usually have dinner?","A":"6.30","B":"7.15","C":"7.30","D":"8.00","answer":"7.30"},{"question":"What do they drink for dinner?","A":"iced tea","B":"orange juice","C":"iced coffee","D":"soda","answer":"orange juice"},{"question":"What do they usually have for dinner?","A":"beef","B":"meal","C":"potatoes","D":"chips","answer":"potatoes"},{"question":"Where do they have dinner on Saturday evenings?","A":"at a hotel","B":"at home","C":"at their friend\'s house","D":"at a restaurant","answer":"at a restaurant"},{"question":"Petty is talking about her __","A":"everyday life","B":"work","C":"husband","D":"job","answer":"everyday life"}]},{"passage":["One morning Nasreddin left his house with six donkeys to go to the market. After a time, he got tired and got on to one of them. He counted the donkeys, and there were only five, so he got off and went to look for the sixth. He looked and looked but did not find it, he went back to the donkeys and counted them again. This time there were six, so he got on to one of them again and they all started","After a few minutes he counted the donkeys again, and again there were only five! While he was counting again a friend of his passed, and Nasreddin said to him, I left my house with six donkeys; then had five; then I had six again, and now I have only five! Look! One, two, three, four, five.","\'But, Nasreddin,\' said his friend, \'You are sitting on a donkey too! That is the sixth! And you are the seventh!\'"],"questions":[{"question":"What did Nasreddin do one morning?","A":"He went to the shop.","B":"He went to his mother\'s house.","C":"He went to the market.","D":"He went to his friend\'s house.","answer":"He went to the market."},{"question":"How many donkeys did he have with him?","A":"four","B":"five","C":"six","D":"seven","answer":"six "},{"question":"What did he do when he got tired?","A":"He sold the donkeys","B":"He sold one of the donkeys.","C":"He stopped to have a rest.","D":"He sat on one of the donkeys","answer":"He sat on one of the donkeys"},{"question":"How many donkeys did he count when he was sitting on the donkey?","A":"four","B":"five","C":"six","D":"seven","answer":"five"},{"question":"What did his friend say to Nasreddin?","A":"His friend said Nasreddin had seven donkeys","B":"His friend said Nasreddin had five donkeys","C":"His friend said Nasreddin had one donkey","D":"His friend said Nasreddin was the seventh donkey","answer":"His friend said Nasreddin was the seventh donkey"}]},{"passage":["I was born in Newcastle, a city in the North East of England, Newcastle is on the bank of the River Tyne. It is quite big, with a population of about 200,000 people. There is a cathedral and a university. There are five bridges over the River Tyne, which links Newcastle to the next town, Gateshead, where there is one of the biggest shopping centres in the world. A few years ago, the main industries were shipbuilding and coal mining, but now the chemical and soap industries are important. I moved to London ten years ago but I often return to Newcastle. I miss the people, who are very friendly, and I miss the beautiful countryside near the city, where there are so many hills and streams."],"questions":[{"question":"Newcastle is_____","A":"a city near the North East of England","B":"a city in the North of England","C":"a city in the North East of England","D":"a small town in England","answer":"a city in the North East of England"},{"question":"The population of Newcastle is________","A":"200,000 people","B":"fewer than 200,000 people","C":"more than 200,000 people","D":"about 200,000 people","answer":"about 200,000 people"},{"question":"How many bridges are there over the River Tyne?","A":"two","B":"three","C":"four","D":"five","answer":"five"},{"question":"Gateshead has one of_____ in the world.","A":"the largest rivers","B":"the most important shipbuilding industries","C":"the biggest shopping centres","D":"the most beautiful countryside","answer":"the biggest shopping centres"},{"question":"According to the passage, the writer______","A":"is still living in Newcastle","B":"has never returned to Newcastle","C":"doesn\'t live in Newcastle anymore!","D":"has come back to live in Newcastle","answer":"doesn\'t live in Newcastle anymore!"},{"question":"What is one of the most important industries in Newcastle now?","A":"shipbuilding","B":"coal mining","C":"chemical industry","D":"tourism","answer":"chemical industry"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT true about Newcastle?","A":"It is next to Gateshead.","B":"Its main industry now is shipbuilding","C":"It has a cathedral and a university","D":"Its people are friendly","answer":"Its main industry now is shipbuilding"},{"question":"What does the author miss about Newcastle?","A":"the university","B":"the cathedral","C":"the shopping centres","D":"the countryside","answer":"the countryside"},{"question":"What is the best title for this passage?","A":"Newcastle - My hometown","B":"Gateshead","C":"River Tyne","D":"London city","answer":"Newcastle - My hometown"}]},{"passage":["Joshua is a ten-year-old boy. His mother is named Anna. His father is name John. His sister is named Lisa. Lisa is eight years old.","The family is on vacation at the beach. Everyone is happy. Joshuais happy because he is playing in the water. Lisa is happy because she is playing in the sand. John and Anna are happy because they are relaxing on the beach. Joshuaand Lis are wearing their swimsuits and goggles. John is wearing sunglasses and an orange T-shirt. Anna is wearing a sun dress and a large hat. She does not want the sun to get in her eyes.","\'We are hungry,\' the children say, \'Is there any food to eat?\' \'Yes,\' says Anna. \'We have sandwiches, oranges, and cookies.\'","\'Yay!\' the children say. They wait for their mother to get the food. Anna gets the food out of her bag. She gives it to the children.","\'Mom, I am thirsty,\' says Lisa. \'Okay, do not worry. We have apple juice for you to drink,\' says Anna \'Thanks,\' says Lisa. She drinks the apple juice and smiles.","The children finish eating lunch and start playing again. John looks at Annu and smiles."],"questions":[{"question":"When you \'play\' (line 4), you do something___________","A":"for free","B":"for money","C":"because you have to","D":"for fun","answer":"for fun"},{"question":"When you \'relax\' (line 5), you_____","A":"exercise","B":"work","C":"rest","D":"jump","answer":"rest"},{"question":"If I am \'wearing\' (line 6) something, it is_______","A":"on my body","B":"on my bed","C":"in my room","D":"in my mind","answer":"on my body"},{"question":"If I am \'hungry\' (line 9), I want something to_______","A":"eat","B":"drink","C":"think","D":"play","answer":"eat"},{"question":"If I am \u201cthirsty\u201d (line 13), I want something to _______","A":"eat","B":"drink","C":"think","D":"play","answer":"drink"},{"question":"What is Joshua doing in the water?","A":"Swimming","B":"Diving","C":"Playing","D":"Surfing","answer":"Playing"},{"question":"What color is John\'s T-shirt?","A":"Yellow","B":"Blue","C":"Green","D":"Orange","answer":"Orange"},{"question":"What does Ann not want?","A":"The sunlight to get in her eyes","B":"Sunbathing in the sun","C":"Sunset in the afternoon","D":"Sunrise in the morning","answer":"The sunlight to get in her eyes"},{"question":"What are John and Anna doing on the bench?","A":"Reading","B":"Playing the guitar","C":"Playing in the sand","D":"Relaxing","answer":"Relaxing"},{"question":"What food is not in the bag?","A":"Sandwiches","B":"Oranges","C":"Apples","D":"Cookies","answer":"Apples"},{"question":"What do the children do after asking about the food?","A":"They wait for John to get the food.","B":"They wait for their mother to get the food","C":"They feel full","D":"They feel tired","answer":"They wait for their mother to get the food"},{"question":"What kind of juice does Lisa drink","A":"Apple","B":"Orange","C":"Peach","D":"Grape","answer":"Apple"},{"question":"The best title for this passage is_______","A":"Family Vacation at the Beach","B":"Family Together","C":"Members of Family","D":"Family on the Lake","answer":"Family Vacation at the Beach"}]},{"passage":["It was two weeks before Christmas, and Mrs. Smith was very busy. She bought a lot of Christmas cards to send to her friends and to her husband\'s friends, and put them on the table in the living-room. Then, when her husband came home from work, she said to him, \'Here are the Christmas cards for our friends, and here are some stamps, a pen and our book of addresses. Will you please write the cards while I am cooking the dinner?\'","Mr. Smith did not say anything, but walked out of the living-room and went to his study. Mrs. Smith was very angry with him, but did not say anything either.","Then a minute later he came back with a box full of Christmas cards. All of them had addresses and stamps on them.","\'These are from last year,\'\' he said, \'I forgot to post them.\'"],"questions":[{"question":"When was Mrs. Smith very busy?","A":"at work","B":"two weeks before Christmas","C":"on Christmas night","D":"after Christmas","answer":"two weeks before Christmas"},{"question":"Who did she buy the cards for?","A":"Her husband","B":"Her friends","C":"Her husband\'s friends","D":"Friends of hers and her husband\'s","answer":"Friends of hers and her husband\'s"},{"question":"What did she want her husband to do?","A":"To sell the cards","B":"To write the cards","C":"To put the cards away","D":"To burn the cards","answer":"To write the cards"},{"question":"What did Mrs. Smith feel when her husband went to his study?","A":"nervous","B":"angry","C":"happy","D":"tired","answer":"angry"},{"question":"Why didn\'t Mr. Smith write the cards?","A":"He didn\'t like it","B":"He did not have a pen.","C":"He had the Christmas cards from last year.","D":"His wife did it for him","answer":"He had the Christmas cards from last year."},{"question":"Why did he still have the cards from last year?","A":"He forgot to post them","B":"He left them at his friend\'s house","C":"He didn\'t want to give them away","D":"He didn\'t have enough money to buy new cards","answer":"He forgot to post them"},{"question":"What can be said about Mr. Smith?","A":"He is a rich person","B":"He often forgets to do things","C":"He is a good cook","D":"He is a postman","answer":"He often forgets to do things"}]},{"passage":["Mrs. Jones was still cleaning the house when her husband came back from work. She was wearing dirty, old clothes and no stockings, her hair was not tidy, she had dust on her face, and she looked dirty and tired. Her husband looked at her and said angrily: \u201cIs this what I come home to after a hard day\'s work?\u201d","Mrs. Jones\' neighbor, Mrs. Smith, was there. When she heard Mr. Jones\' words, she quickly said goodbye and ran back to her house. Then she washed, brushed and combed her hair carefully, put on her best dress and her prettiest stockings, painted her face, and waited for her husband to come home.","When he arrived, he was hot and tired. He walked slowly into the house, saw his wife and stopped. Then he shouted angrily, \'And where are you going this evening?"],"questions":[{"question":"What was Mrs. Jones doing?","A":"She was cooking the dinner","B":"She was painting the house","C":"She was cleaning the house","D":"She was washing the clothes","answer":"She was cleaning the house"},{"question":"What was Mrs. Jones wearing?","A":"She was wearing her best dress","B":"She was wearing dirty, old clothes.","C":"She was wearing her prettiest stockings","D":"She was wearing jeans","answer":"She was wearing dirty, old clothes."},{"question":"How did she look?","A":"She looked healthy","B":"She looked happy","C":"She looked tired","D":"She looked sad","answer":"She looked tired"},{"question":"How did her husband feel when he said \'Is this what I came home to after a hard day\'s work?","A":"He felt angry","B":"Hel felt happy","C":"He felt nervous","D":"He felt sorry","answer":"He felt angry"},{"question":"Who was Mrs. Smith?","A":"Mrs. Jones\'s sister","B":"Mrs. Jones\'s mother","C":"Mrs. Jones\' neighbor","D":"Mrs. Jones\'s aunt","answer":"Mrs. Jones\' neighbor"},{"question":"What did she do when she heard Mr. Smith\'s words?","A":"She stood there to watch them talking.","B":"She said goodbye and ran back to her house","C":"She argued with Mr. Smith","D":"She did nothing...","answer":"She said goodbye and ran back to her house"},{"question":"How did Mrs. Smith\'s husband feel when he came home?","A":"He felt excited.","B":"He felt hot and tired.","C":"He felt happy.","D":"He felt nervous","answer":"He felt hot and tired."},{"question":"How many people are there in the story?","A":"two","B":"three","C":"four","D":"five","answer":"four"}]}]')},129:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"John is my best friend, and I am a friend __________.","A":"of him","B":"him","C":"his","D":"of his","answer":"of his"},{"question":"Mary is _______ girl in our class.","A":"the prettiest","B":"prettiest","C":"prettier","D":"the prettier","answer":"the prettiest"},{"question":"I like to play _______ guitar in my free time.","A":"an","B":"a","C":"the","D":"\xd8","answer":"the"},{"question":"The earliest bus from Ho Chi Minh City ________ in Nha Trang at 6:15 every evening.","A":"arrived","B":"is arriving","C":"arrives","D":"would arrive","answer":"arrives"},{"question":"My younger brother ate _______ much ice cream that he had a sore throat.","A":"so","B":"too","C":"enough","D":"far","answer":"so"},{"question":"My sister called me when I _________ dinner.","A":"cooked","B":"was cooking","C":"am cooking","D":"cook","answer":"was cooking"},{"question":"We do not have _______ to make a big cake.","A":"powder enough","B":"enough powder","C":"many powder","D":"powder much","answer":"enough powder"},{"question":"_______do you often talk to in your family?","A":"How","B":"When","C":"Where","D":"Who","answer":"Who"},{"question":"I have had a new hair cut ________ yesterday.","A":"since","B":"for","C":"until","D":"ever","answer":"since"},{"question":"My father was ________ and shouted at me.","A":"anger","B":"angered","C":"angering","D":"angry","answer":"angry"},{"question":"If he comes here, I ________ him do it.","A":"made","B":"make","C":"will make","D":"would make","answer":"will make"},{"question":"I really don\u2019t know what you should do, but I think you _______ talk to your parents.","A":"must","B":"should","C":"might","D":"would ","answer":"should"},{"question":"I am very poor. I don\u2019t have _______ money left now.","A":"any","B":"none","C":"some","D":"no","answer":"any"},{"question":"My family like to go _______ a picnic.","A":"for","B":"in","C":"by","D":"at","answer":"for"},{"question":"John: I\u2019ve two tickets for a play. I wonder if you can go with me? Mary: ___________.","A":"With pleasure. I\u2019m crazy about plays","B":"I think so, and what\u2019s on your mind?","C":"I see what you mean. Let me think","D":"Yes, I\u2019m in a great hurry.","answer":"With pleasure. I\u2019m crazy about plays"},{"question":"Your brother has come back from the U.S, ______?","A":"isn\u2019t he","B":"hasn\u2019t he","C":"didn\u2019t he","D":"doesn\u2019t he","answer":"hasn\u2019t he"},{"question":"Bob ________ the package for the old man.","A":"put","B":"helped","C":"called","D":"carried","answer":"carried"},{"question":"He couldn\u2019t go far because he was afraid of _______ by air.","A":"to travel","B":"travelling","C":"to be travelling","D":"being to travel","answer":"travelling"},{"question":"I can\u2019t swim, and ________ can my sister.","A":"either","B":"too","C":"neither","D":"so","answer":"neither"},{"question":"Peter is a successful _________. His students admire him a lot.","A":"teacher","B":"player","C":"seller","D":"singer","answer":"teacher"}]')},130:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"He is__ jacket.","A":"wearing","B":"worn","C":"wore","D":"wear","answer":"wearing"},{"question":"Would you mind____ the window?","A":"open","B":"to open","C":"opening","D":"to opening","answer":"opening"},{"question":"A:___ you? B: Yes, please get my luggage from the car.","A":"Do I help","B":"Have I help","C":"Can I help","D":"Am i helping","answer":"Can I help"},{"question":"We haven\'t heard ____ the result was","A":"what","B":"which","C":"that","D":"about","answer":"what"},{"question":"You have been here_______","A":"is it","B":"isn\'t it","C":"don\'t you","D":"haven\u2019t you","answer":"haven\u2019t you"},{"question":"They stopped_____ for her when it grew dark.","A":"looking","B":"have looked","C":"looked","D":"to be locked","answer":"looking"},{"question":"Dick and Joan greeted_______","A":"himself","B":"herself","C":"themselves","D":"each other","answer":"each other"},{"question":"It\'s very dark here. Please turn the light ______","A":"of","B":"up","C":"on","D":"in","answer":"on"},{"question":"Betty is my friend. She is a friend of _______","A":"me","B":"my","C":"mine","D":"I","answer":"mine"},{"question":"_______ you angry with him?","A":"Do","B":"Why","C":"Are","D":"Have","answer":"Are"},{"question":"Please ask her___","A":"that waits","B":"wait","C":"to wait","D":"for waiting","answer":"to wait"},{"question":"_____ you got a radio at home?","A":"Have","B":"Are","C":"Do","D":"has","answer":"Have"},{"question":"I usually spend two hours ____ English in the evening.","A":"to be learned","B":"learning","C":"learned","D":"learn","answer":"learning"},{"question":"She\'d rather stay at home__ go shopping.","A":"of","B":"but","C":"so","D":"than","answer":"than"},{"question":"I___ to her since last Wednesday morning.","A":"haven\'t talked","B":"don\'t talk","C":"didn\'t talk","D":"am not talking","answer":"haven\'t talked"},{"question":"They _____in Warsaw for about ten years.","A":"live","B":"living","C":"lives","D":"have lived","answer":"have lived"},{"question":"I will not go to Cambridge if it_____ tomorrow.","A":"rain","B":"would rain","C":"rains","D":"raining","answer":"rains"},{"question":"When _____ you go to work yesterday?","A":"were","B":"was","C":"did","D":"have","answer":"did"},{"question":"I _____ work in China when I graduated from university.","A":"used to","B":"mustn\'t","C":"use","D":"need","answer":"used to"},{"question":"The lesson was so__ that we fell asleep easily.","A":"bored","B":"boredom","C":"boring","D":"bore","answer":"boring"}]')},131:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"She agreed ____ the job as soon as possible.","A":"start","B":"starting","C":"starts","D":"to start","answer":"to start"},{"question":"he TV program was so ____ that I felt asleep.","A":"surprising","B":"tired","C":"annoyed","D":"boring","answer":"boring"},{"question":"There were   ____ people at the party! There was nowhere to dance.","A":"so many","B":"such a","C":"such","D":"so much","answer":"so many"},{"question":"I hate being late. I like to arrive ___time.","A":"by","B":"on","C":"at","D":"for","answer":"on"},{"question":"I\'m going to bed when this TV program_____","A":"ended","B":"will end","C":"is going to end","D":"ends","answer":"ends"},{"question":"We arrived______ the station five minutes late.","A":"to","B":"at","C":"for","D":"on","answer":"at"},{"question":"She ______work on Monday. It is her day off.","A":"must","B":"have to","C":"doesn\'t have to","D":"didn\u2019t","answer":"doesn\'t have to"},{"question":"She was very ill and_____ died, but fortunately, she got better.","A":"nearly","B":"carefully","C":"too","D":"usually","answer":"nearly"},{"question":"He is one of the_____ boys in the class.","A":"funnier","B":"most funny","C":"more funny","D":"funniest","answer":"funniest"},{"question":"You have the same hobby _______Jack.","A":"as","B":"with","C":"So","D":"like","answer":"as"},{"question":"The hotel __________we stayed was very comfortable.","A":"who","B":"where","C":"Whose","D":"when","answer":"where"},{"question":"I didn\'t like this city. The streets were so dirty and the air was so______","A":"pollute","B":"polluted","C":"to pollution","D":"polluting","answer":"polluted"},{"question":"This is the place in  ________ he was born.","A":"which","B":"whose","C":"where","D":"there","answer":"which"},{"question":"Peter enjoyed_________ to the zoo when he was small.","A":"taken","B":"being taken","C":"taking","D":"to take","answer":"being taken"},{"question":"When she called, I_____ a bath.","A":"am having","B":"was having","C":"were having","D":"had","answer":"was having"},{"question":"Rolls Royce cars ___ in England.","A":"were made","B":"is made","C":"makes","D":"are made","answer":"are made"},{"question":"Is there___ traffic in your town?","A":"A many","B":"a few","C":"some","D":"much","answer":"much"},{"question":"Last year, we managed________ a new house.","A":"bought","B":"to buying","C":"to buy","D":"buy","answer":"to buy"},{"question":"I\'m looking forward______ more free time","A":"to have","B":"having","C":"to having","D":"of having","answer":"to having"},{"question":"Please ask______ help if you want.","A":"for","B":"to","C":"or","D":"in","answer":"for"}]')},132:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"Many thousands children have accidents in their homes.","A":"thousands","B":"have","C":"in","D":"their","answer":"thousands"},{"question":"Many children have been bad burned because they have stood too near a fire.","A":"Many","B":"bad","C":"because","D":"too","answer":"bad"},{"question":"The moon revolves once on its axis each time it orbit the Earth.","A":"revolves","B":"on","C":"orbit","D":"the","answer":"orbit"},{"question":"A young man jumped into the river yesterday\u2019s morning to save a twelve-year-old boy.","A":"jumped","B":"yesterday\u2019s","C":"a","D":"twelve-year-old","answer":"yesterday\u2019s"},{"question":"James McNeil Whistler was one of the first appreciating the beauty of Japanese colour prints.","A":"was","B":"appreciating","C":"of","D":"prints","answer":"appreciating"},{"question":"This museum is on the center of the town, and a few meters from the cathedral.","A":"on","B":"the","C":"and","D":"from","answer":"on"},{"question":"Most major manufacturing countries of Europe had toy industrial in the last century.","A":"Most","B":"manufacturing","C":"industrial","D":"last","answer":"industrial"},{"question":"About three thousand years ago, there were no shops, and people don\u2019t use money to buy things.","A":"About","B":"ago","C":"there","D":"don\u2019t use","answer":"don\u2019t use"},{"question":"Although fire and hot water causes most accidents in their homes, many children cut themselves with knives.","A":"Although","B":"causes","C":"themselves","D":"with","answer":"causes"},{"question":"The first paper money has been made by the Chinese, and the first banks appeared in Italy.","A":"has been made","B":"the Chinese","C":"banks","D":"in","answer":"has been made"},{"question":"When you have a pet, it is very important that you look for it properly.","A":"When","B":"very","C":"for","D":"properly","answer":"for"},{"question":"Among the months of November and May wind blows from the west in most parts of Indonesia.","A":"Among","B":"of","C":"wind","D":"most","answer":"Among"},{"question":"Nathan often goes to my house, and we are very close friend.","A":"often","B":"to","C":"we","D":"friend","answer":"friend"},{"question":"Some people prefer the dry season where they can sit outside and enjoy the cool evening.","A":"prefer","B":"where","C":"outside","D":"the","answer":"where"},{"question":"Birds sing to give information, and their songs are its language.","A":"to give","B":"and","C":"are","D":"its","answer":"its"},{"question":"Candidates for the Nobel prizes are judging by Swedish and Norwegian academies and institutes.","A":"for","B":"the","C":"are judging","D":"academies","answer":"are judging"},{"question":"Of the six inner planets, Mars is the closer to the Earth.","A":"Of","B":"inner","C":"planets","D":"closer","answer":"closer"},{"question":"Bananas widely believed to grow on trees, but this is incorrect.","A":"widely believed","B":"on","C":"but","D":"this","answer":"widely believed"},{"question":"Road maps and picture signs guide, warn, and introduce people.","A":"Road","B":"and","C":"picture","D":"introduce","answer":"introduce"},{"question":"Many children have to go to hospital because of they thought medicine was sweets.","A":"have","B":"hospital","C":"because","D":"was","answer":"because"},{"question":"After the invention of the oil lamp, men used burning sticks as torches.","A":"After","B":"the","C":"used","D":"as","answer":"After"},{"question":"I have known your father when he was very young.","A":"known","B":"your","C":"when","D":"young","answer":"when"},{"question":"Many years ago, it was a king who was often ill and very bad-tempered.","A":"years","B":"it","C":"who","D":"bad-tempered","answer":"it"},{"question":"I have a stomachache and headache every day, because I can\u2019t concentrate on my studies.","A":"stomachache","B":"every day","C":"because","D":"on","answer":"because"},{"question":"Body language transmits ideas or thoughts by certain actions, either intentionally nor unintentionally.","A":"transmits","B":"by","C":"actions","D":"nor","answer":"nor"},{"question":"Jim went for jogging yesterday morning. He felt cold because of the strong wind and came home soon.","A":"for","B":"felt","C":"strong","D":"came","answer":"for"},{"question":"If you want to have a pet, you can buy ones from a pet shop but you must be careful not to buy a sick animal.","A":"If","B":"have","C":"ones","D":"must","answer":"ones"},{"question":"Jack and Dan walked altogether. Thinking Jack was a fool, Dan planned to play a trick on him.","A":"altogether","B":"Thinking","C":"was","D":"play","answer":"altogether"},{"question":"The first society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals was found in England in 1821.","A":"The","B":"society","C":"found","D":"in","answer":"found"},{"question":"After landed on the soil of Mars, Viking I performed many scientific experiments and took numerous pictures.","A":"landed","B":"of","C":"scientific","D":"took","answer":"landed"}]')},133:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"It is difficult forgiving someone when he hurts you.","A":"It","B":"forgiving","C":"when","D":"you","answer":"forgiving"},{"question":"She has become president in 1979 after the elections","A":"has become","B":"president","C":"in","D":"elections","answer":"has become"},{"question":"Mary likes chatting cooking, and to swim","A":"likes","B":"chatting","C":"cooking","D":"to swim","answer":"to swim"},{"question":"She is one of my best friend in my life","A":"one","B":"best","C":"friend","D":"life","answer":"friend"},{"question":"Even though the film was extremely interested, he did not watch it","A":"Even though","B":"was","C":"interested","D":"watch","answer":"interested"},{"question":"The student should to study as hard as he can.","A":"The student","B":"to study","C":"hard","D":"he can","answer":"to study"},{"question":"The phone rung while I was washing the dishes.","A":"phone","B":"rung","C":"washing","D":"dishes","answer":"rung"},{"question":"The song to which we listening last night was beautiful.","A":"The song","B":"which","C":"listening","D":"was","answer":"listening"},{"question":"She bought an wonderful present for him on his birthday last year","A":"bought","B":"an","C":"for","D":"on","answer":"an"},{"question":"This school is only for children whose first languages is now English.","A":"This","B":"only","C":"whose","D":"languages","answer":"languages"},{"question":"Although he was tired, but he still went to work I am happy.  I am tired.","A":"he was","B":"tired","C":"but","D":"to work","answer":"but"},{"question":"Using bicycles in big cities is good because they are not only clean and easy to park.","A":"is","B":"because","C":"only","D":"and","answer":"and"},{"question":"Do you get on well with the person whom lives next door?","A":"get on","B":"the person","C":"whom","D":"next door","answer":"whom"},{"question":"It was think to have been built in the 14th century.","A":"was think","B":"been built","C":"14th","D":"century","answer":"was think"},{"question":"That sign is too small read, isn\'t it?","A":"That","B":"is","C":"read","D":"it","answer":"read"},{"question":"It took me three years finishing this project","A":"took","B":"years","C":"finishing","D":"project","answer":"finishing"},{"question":"The last person to leave the room must to turn off the light.","A":"last person","B":"to leave","C":"must to turn","D":"the light","answer":"must to turn"},{"question":"My close friend, which I\'ve not met for 3 years, has just returned from India","A":"which","B":"I\'ve","C":"for","D":"just returned","answer":"which"},{"question":"He used to get up early on the mornings because he had to go to work on time","A":"used to","B":"get up","C":"on the mornings","D":"on time","answer":"on the mornings"},{"question":"They working in a hospital sponsored by the government.","A":"working","B":"in","C":"sponsored","D":"by","answer":"working"},{"question":"The weather was such hot that I couldn\'t get out of the house","A":"The weather","B":"such","C":"that","D":"out of","answer":"such"},{"question":"Both Tom with Ann were late for class","A":"with","B":"were","C":"late","D":"for","answer":"with"},{"question":"Your grandfather could speak five languages, can he?","A":"Your","B":"speak","C":"languages","D":"can he","answer":"can he"},{"question":"She spoke in a very low voice, but I can understand what she said","A":"in a very","B":"but","C":"can","D":"she said","answer":"can"},{"question":"Every night he go to bed at 11 p.m","A":"Every","B":"go","C":"to bed","D":"at","answer":"go"},{"question":"Mary, who is living near my house, is too young getting married","A":"who","B":"near","C":"too","D":"getting married","answer":"getting married"},{"question":"If the weather will be fine tomorrow, we can play tennis","A":"If","B":"will be","C":"tomorrow","D":"can","answer":"will be"},{"question":"He learnt so hardly that lie got the highest result in the exam","A":"learnt","B":"hardly","C":"the","D":"exam","answer":"hardly"},{"question":"He is understand my ideas better now.","A":"is understand","B":"ideas","C":"better","D":"now","answer":"is understand"},{"question":"When he passes his driving test, he will be able go to Germany every weekend","A":"When","B":"passes","C":"able go","D":"every weekend","answer":"able go"}]')},134:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"f I were there, I will give you a call at once","A":"there","B":"will give","C":"a call","D":"at once","answer":"will give"},{"question":"Jane and Peter are so nice people that they are loved by their neighbours","A":"so","B":"they ","C":"loved ","D":"by ","answer":"so"},{"question":"We decided renting a house with a swimming pool yesterday.","A":"renting ","B":"house ","C":"a","D":"swimming pool","answer":"renting"},{"question":"Despite John was ill, he tried to go to work on time.","A":"Despite ","B":"ill","C":"to go","D":"on ","answer":"Despite"},{"question":"If I had enough money, I will buy a bigger house in the city.","A":"had ","B":"money","C":"buy ","D":"in ","answer":"had"},{"question":"I had a few problems, but James gave me some good advices.","A":"a few","B":"but ","C":"gave ","D":"advices","answer":"advices"},{"question":"She refused to being there at the time of the party because she was too busy.","A":"to being","B":"at ","C":"of ","D":"too ","answer":"to being"},{"question":"Mary is so fond in reading comic books in the evening.","A":"so ","B":"in ","C":"books ","D":"","answer":"in"},{"question":"He said me that he didn\'t mean to hurt me.","A":"said ","B":"that ","C":"he ","D":" to hurt","answer":"said"},{"question":"I talked to the girl who dog bit the postman","A":"talked ","B":"who ","C":"bit ","D":"","answer":"who"},{"question":"Were your parents worrying when you told them your exam results?","A":"your ","B":"worrying ","C":"told ","D":"results","answer":"worrying"},{"question":"Maria is interested on playing badminton with her friends every morning.","A":"is ","B":"on ","C":"with ","D":"every ","answer":"on"},{"question":"I will never forget to meeting him for the first time in my life.","A":"I will","B":"to meeting","C":"for ","D":"first ","answer":"to meeting"},{"question":"You had better get your hair to cut at the hairdresser\'s.","A":"had better","B":"your ","C":"to cut","D":"hairdresser\'s","answer":"to cut"},{"question":"Jack and his wife lived next to me since their son, Thomas, was born.","A":"lived ","B":"to ","C":"son","D":"was ","answer":"lived"},{"question":"I wish becoming a teacher after leaving the university next year. ","A":"becoming ","B":"after ","C":"the ","D":"next ","answer":"becoming"},{"question":"Honestly, Rome was much hotter than I expected.","A":"Honestly","B":"much hotter","C":"expected","D":"______","answer":"______"},{"question":"You can tell me your secret and I didn\u2019t tell anyone.","A":"can ","B":"your ","C":"didn\u2019t ","D":"anyone","answer":"didn\u2019t"},{"question":"Of all the book I have read, I love \'Romeo and Juliet\' most.","A":"Of ","B":"book ","C":"love ","D":"most","answer":"book"},{"question":"I have the habit of going to bed on 9 p.m. every Saturday.","A":"have ","B":"of ","C":"to ","D":"on ","answer":"on"},{"question":"Neither I nor she like to talk about politics","A":"Neither ","B":"like ","C":"talk ","D":"politics","answer":"like"},{"question":"I used to going fishing with my dad when I was a little boy.","A":"going ","B":"with ","C":"when ","D":"a little","answer":"going"},{"question":"The man I met yesterday told me that I were pretty.","A":"The ","B":"what did I do","C":"at ","D":"","answer":"what did I do"},{"question":"I have got much homeworks to do tonight, so I can\'t come to your party","A":"I have","B":"homeworks","C":"so ","D":"can\'t ","answer":"homeworks"},{"question":"It took me half an hour travelling from my house to his school.","A":"me ","B":"an ","C":"travelling ","D":"to ","answer":"travelling"},{"question":"Some people don\'t go out at night because of they are frightened.","A":"don\'t ","B":"at night","C":"because of","D":"frightened","answer":"because of"},{"question":"You shouldn\'t having a late dinner as it is not good for your health.","A":"having ","B":"late ","C":"as ","D":"for ","answer":"having"},{"question":"Everyone are eager to welcome a new member of the family","A":"are","B":"to ","C":"new ","D":"of ","answer":"are"},{"question":"He often goes to the concert at Saturday night to relax.","A":"goes ","B":"the ","C":"at ","D":"to relax","answer":"at"},{"question":"She asked me what did I do yesterday at school.","A":"asked ","B":"what did I do","C":"at ","D":"","answer":"what did I do"}]')},135:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"passage":["When Nancy was about seven, a travelling circus came to her town and she still remembers what a strong impression it made on her. She loved all the characters so she dreamt of running away to join them. She seriously considered all the possibilities: lion tamer, elephant handler, acrobat, trapeze artist, but in the end she decided to be a clown. She remembers spending long hours at her mother\u2019s dressing table, putting on make-up to create a clown\u2019s face and then making faces in front of the mirror. Unfortunately, she couldn\u2019t run away to join the circus."],"questions":[{"question":"What happened when Nancy was seven years old?","A":"She made an impression on a travelling circus.","B":"She saw a travelling circus in her town.","C":"She joined a travelling circus to run away.","D":"She became a clown for a travelling circus.","answer":"She saw a travelling circus in her town."},{"question":"What does the word \u201cit\u201d in line 2 refer to?","A":"her town","B":"a strong impression","C":"a travelling circus","D":"a character","answer":"a travelling circus"},{"question":"Why did Nancy want to join the circus?","A":"Because she could travel out of her town.","B":"Because she loved to act as a clown.","C":"Because she loved all the characters.","D":"Because she was a serious performer.","answer":"Because she loved all the characters."},{"question":"What is the word \u201cpossibilities\u201d in line 3 closest in meaning to?","A":"choices","B":"chances","C":"prospects","D":"threats","answer":"choices"},{"question":"What did Nancy finally choose to become?","A":"An elephant handler","B":"A lion tamer","C":"A trapeze artist","D":"A clown","answer":"A clown"},{"question":"Why did Nany spend long hours at her mother\u2019s dressing table?","A":"To remove the make-up","B":"To create a clown costume","C":"To design a portrait","D":"To wear make-up","answer":"To create a clown costume"}]},{"passage":["John plays the piano. He plays it very well. He started playing the piano when he was six years old. After a year, he played better and better. Now he is 13 years old. He is very good. He won one piano contest after another. A famous piano teacher heard him play the piano. The teacher said, \u201cI want to bring you to New York. I will teach you how to be even better. I will teach you how to be the best piano player in the whole world.\u201d He didn\u2019t like that idea. He wanted to stay at home. He wanted to stay with his parents and his friends. His parents wanted him to go. They said they would visit him in New York every weekend."],"questions":[{"question":"How did John play the piano?","A":"Very healthily","B":"Very brilliantly","C":"Very intelligently","D":"Very modestly","answer":"Very brilliantly"},{"question":"When did John begin playing the piano?","A":"When he was five.","B":"When he was four.","C":"When he was six.","D":"When he was seven","answer":"When he was six."},{"question":"How old is John now according to the passage?","A":"Seven","B":"Six","C":"Thirteen","D":"Eighteen","answer":"Thirteen"},{"question":"Which of the following best paraphrases this sentence: \u201cHe won one piano contest after another\u201d?","A":"He was the winner of many piano contests.","B":"He won all of the piano contests.","C":"He only won one piano contest.","D":"He was better at one piano contest then at the other.","answer":"He was the winner of many piano contests."},{"question":"Who wanted to bring John to New York?","A":"His piano teacher","B":"A person who met him at a piano contest.","C":"His parents","D":"A piano teacher hearing him play the piano.","answer":"A piano teacher hearing him play the piano."},{"question":"What does the phrase \u201cthat idea\u201d refer to?","A":"That he would travel to New York and be taught to be the best.","B":"That he should have learnt to be the best among piano players.","C":"That someone would teach him how to play the piano better.","D":"That playing the piano in New York would change his world.","answer":"That he would travel to New York and be taught to be the best."},{"question":"Which of the following is true about John?","A":"He became locally famous for playing the piano as a child.","B":"He took part in more than one piano contest when he was 13.","C":"He refused to go to New York to improve his piano skills.","D":"He was forced by his parents to play the piano in New York.","answer":"He was forced by his parents to play the piano in New York."},{"question":"What is the passage mainly about?","A":"A famous piano player","B":"A boy who plays the piano","C":"The development of a piano player","D":"Benefits of playing the piano","answer":"A boy who plays the piano"}]},{"passage":["Television is one of man\u2019s most important advances in communication. It brings images and sounds from around the world into millions of homes. A person with a TV set can sit in this house and watch the president make a speech or visit a foreign country on television. Viewers can see and learn about people, places and things in far-off lands. In addition to all those tings, TV brings its viewers a steady stream of programs which are designed to entertain. In fact, TV is very useful for our spiritual life, and it is always a cheap source of entertainment."],"questions":[{"question":"What is true about television?","A":"It makes people\u2019s lives more useful.","B":"It connects millions of homes worldwide.","C":"It provides a lot of benefits to people.","D":"It inspires people to travel far away.","answer":"It provides a lot of benefits to people."},{"question":"What does the word \u201cIt\u201d in line 1 refer to?","A":"Communication","B":"Advance","C":"The world","D":"Television","answer":"Television"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT mentioned as an advantage of television?","A":"A source of entertainment","B":"A source of knowledge","C":"A source of spiritual practices","D":"A source of news","answer":"A source of spiritual practices"},{"question":"What is the word \u201csteady\u201d closest in meaning to?","A":"unchanging","B":"constant","C":"balanced","D":"secured","answer":"constant"},{"question":"What is the main purpose of the passage?","A":"To encourage people to buy TV sets","B":"To stress the importance of people\u2019s mental lives","C":"To prove how significant television is","D":"To introduce a new way of virtual travelling","answer":"To prove how significant television is"}]},{"passage":["Marie Curie was born in 1867. She is one of the greatest scientists ever to have lived. She was a pioneer in the field of radioactivity and discovered the chemical elements radium and polonium. Curie is the only person ever to win two Nobel Prizes in two different sciences. Other achievements include being the first female professor at the University of Paris.","Curie was born in Warsaw, Poland. Her father was a maths and physics teacher and was a big influence on Marie\u2019s early education. From an early age, Marie was an exceptional student with an amazing memory. She often went without food and sleep to study. Her brilliant mind led her to Paris to study and conduct her research.","She met her future husband Pierre Curie at the university. He considered Marie to be a genius and instantly wanted to work with her. They got married and spent most of their time together in their laboratory studying radioactive materials. Their research led to the discovery of radium, for which they were honoured with the Nobel Prize for Physics in 1903."],"questions":[{"question":"Which of the following is true about Marie Curie?","A":"She was born in the 19th century.","B":"She was the greatest chemist of her era.","C":"She studied radioactivity because of her husband.","D":"She was the first female professor ever.","answer":"She was born in the 19th century."},{"question":"What did Marie find from her research?","A":"Radioactive elements","B":"Some chemical reactions","C":"Radium\u2019s usefulness in medicine","D":"How to produce polonium from radium","answer":"Radioactive elements"},{"question":"How many Nobel Prizes did Marie win?","A":"One","B":"Two","C":"Three","D":"Four","answer":"Two"},{"question":"Where was Marie born?","A":"Paris","B":"Wattrelos","C":"Warsaw","D":"Poznan","answer":"Warsaw"},{"question":"Who had an impact on Marie\u2019s early education?","A":"Her grandmother","B":"Her grandfather","C":"Her mother","D":"Her father","answer":"Her mother"},{"question":"What did Marie often do when she was young?","A":"She often learnt from exceptional students.","B":"She often studied without eating or sleeping.","C":"She often went to Paris to conduct research.","D":"She often made use of her memory in research.","answer":"She often studied without eating or sleeping."},{"question":"Why did Marie\u2019s husband want to work with her before their marriage?","A":"Because he adored her ability to work hard.","B":"Because she showed a natural ability in science.","C":"Because he wanted to learn from her discovery.","D":"Because she instantly responded to his curiosity.","answer":"Because she showed a natural ability in science."},{"question":"Where did Marie and her husband spend most their time after their marriage?","A":"In leading universities","B":"In their house","C":"In their offices","D":"In their laboratory","answer":"In their laboratory"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT true about the Nobel Prize of Physics mentioned in the passage?","A":"It was awarded in 1903.","B":"It was for a great chemical discovery.","C":"It was granted to a couple.","D":"It was given at the University of Paris.","answer":"It was given at the University of Paris."}]},{"passage":["Saturday morning meant one thing for Susan \u2013 doing the laundry. She hated doing the laundry. Unenthusiastically, she took the pillow cases off all the pillows. Then she removed the fitted sheet from the mattress. She took the towel off the towel bar in the bathroom. She grabbed a couple of dirty dish towels out of the kitchen, and looked all around her apartment for anything else that needed washing.","In the corner of her living room, a can of coins sat on top of the file cabinet. She fished out seven quarters. She opened the cabinet under her kitchen sink and grabbed a plastic bottle of liquid detergent.","Finally, she set her electronic timer for 35 minutes. The timer would remind her that the washing was done, and that it was time to go back downstairs and put the clothes into the dryer for 40 minutes. Without the timer, Susan would completely forget to check her clothes.","Susan carried the laundry basket downstairs. How happy she would be when laundry was done for this week. As she approached the laundry room, she heard a familiar sound. The sound was the washer washing and the dryer drying. One of her neighbors had got there before her. Muttering, Susan took her basket back upstairs."],"questions":[{"question":"What is the word \u201cUnenthusiastically\u201d in line 2 closest meaning to?","A":"Reluctantly","B":"Joyfully","C":"Hopelessly","D":"Patiently","answer":"Reluctantly"},{"question":"Which of the following did Susan do before the other?","A":"She looked all around her apartment for anything else.","B":"She grabbed some dirty dish towels out of the kitchen.","C":"She removed the fitted sheet from the mattress.","D":"She opened the cabinet under her kitchen sink.","answer":"She removed the fitted sheet from the mattress."},{"question":"Which of the following did NOT need washing?","A":"The fitted sheet","B":"The towel bar","C":"The dish towels","D":"The pillow cases","answer":"The towel bar"},{"question":"What is the word grabbed in line 3 closest meaning to?","A":"received","B":"obtained","C":"collected","D":"took","answer":"collected"},{"question":"How long does it take to dry the laundry?","A":"20 minutes","B":"30 minutes","C":"40 minutes","D":"50 minutes","answer":"40 minutes"},{"question":"Which of the following is true about Susan?","A":"She was paid to do the laundry on Saturday mornings.","B":"She had no interest in doing the laundry herself.","C":"She had the laundry done by a neighbor once a week.","D":"She shared the liquid detergent with heir neighbors.","answer":"She had no interest in doing the laundry herself."},{"question":"Why was Susan happy?","A":"Because she heard a familiar sound in the laundry room.","B":"Because she got to the laundry room before her neighbors.","C":"Because she was carrying her laundry basket downstairs.","D":"Because she thought she would soon finish doing the laundry.","answer":"Because she thought she would soon finish doing the laundry."}]},{"passage":["A famous poet came on a visit to a lady who always said that she was fond of literature and especially of poetry. When they sat down to tea, the poet wondered whether she had received the little book of poems he had sent her. With a charming smile, the lady said to him that the poems were splendid and she would like to read some from the book, but she could not remember where she had put it. While her little daughter did not seem to care about it, her little son was ready with the answer: \u201cUnder the leg of the table, Mama, to make it steady.\u201d"],"questions":[{"question":"Which of the following is true about the famous poet mentioned in the passage?","A":"He came to a lady\u2019s house.","B":"He was fond of a lady\u2019s poems.","C":"He drank tea with a lady\u2019s son.","D":"He wondered about a lady\u2019s poems.","answer":"He came to a lady\u2019s house."},{"question":"How was the lady\u2019s smile?","A":"Encouraging","B":"Inviting","C":"Attractive","D":"Supportive","answer":"Attractive"},{"question":"What did the lady think of the poems in the book?","A":"Sparking","B":"Impressive","C":"Practical","D":"Dreamy","answer":"Impressive"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT mentioned about the lady?","A":"She was keen on literature.","B":"She was given a book of poems.","C":"She already read the whole book.","D":"She wanted to read the book of poem.","answer":"She already read the whole book."},{"question":"Where did the lady put the book of poems?","A":"Near the tea pot","B":"In her bedroom","C":"Under the leg of the table","D":"On the table","answer":"Under the leg of the table"},{"question":"Who told the lady about where she put the book of poems?","A":"The poet","B":"Her son","C":"Her daughter","D":"No one","answer":"Her son"},{"question":"What does the word \u201cit\u201d in line 5 refer to?","A":"the book","B":"the answer","C":"the leg","D":"the table","answer":"the table"}]},{"passage":["Today English is one of the major languages in the world. However, in Shakespeare\u2019s time, only a few million people spoke English. In fact, this language was not thought to be very important by the other nations of Europe, and it was unknown to the rest of the world.","English has become a world language because of its establishment as a mother tongue outside England, in all of the continents of the world. This exporting of English began in the seventeenth century, with the first settlements in North America. Above all, it is the great growth of population in the United States, assisted by massive immigration in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, that has given the English language its present standing in the world.","People who speak English fall into one of three groups: those who have learned it as their native language; those who have learned it as a second language in a society that is mainly bilingual; and those who are forced to use it for a practical purpose: administrative, professional, or educational. One person in seven of the world\u2019s entire population belongs to one of these three groups. Incredibly enough, 75% of the world\u2019s mails and 60% of the world\u2019s telephone calls are in English."],"questions":[{"question":"Which of the following is true about English in Shakespeare\u2019s time?","A":"It was a common language in most European countries.","B":"It was popularly used inside and outside England.","C":"It was spoken by a small number of people worldwide.","D":"It was thought to be significant for global communication.","answer":"It was spoken by a small number of people worldwide."},{"question":"Why has English become a world language?","A":"Because it is the first language of many people throughout the world.","B":"Because it is attractive to mothers on every continent.","C":"Because the population using it in England has increased.","D":"Because more English people have settled in North America.","answer":"Because it is the first language of many people throughout the world."},{"question":"Where was English exported to first?","A":"South America","B":"West America","C":"North America","D":"East America","answer":"North America"},{"question":"When was English first exported to places outside of England?","A":"In the sixteenth century","B":"In the seventeenth century","C":"In the eighteenth century","D":"In the nineteenth century","answer":"In the seventeenth century"},{"question":"Which of the following is true according to the passage?","A":"Two thirds of the global population use English as their first language.","B":"The massive immigration helped to spread English across the world.","C":"The United States encouraged its people to use more English.","D":"English has been used as a world language since it was exported to North America.","answer":"The massive immigration helped to spread English across the world."},{"question":"How many groups of people speaking English are mentioned?","A":"Two","B":"Three","C":"Four","D":"Five","answer":"Three"},{"question":"According to the passage, for which purposes are people made to use English?","A":"Communicative, administrative, and educational purposes","B":"Administrative, professional, and communicative purposes","C":"Professional, communicative, and educational purposes","D":"Administrative, professional, and educational purposes","answer":"Administrative, professional, and educational purposes"},{"question":"Why does the author mention the percentage of the world\u2019s  mails and telephone calls in English?","A":"To illustrate the purposes for using English","B":"To encourage the use of mails and telephone calls","C":"To stress the popularity of English in the world","D":"To compare the use of mails and telephone calls","answer":"To stress the popularity of English in the world"}]}]')},160:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"passage":["It is very important to have healthy teeth. Good teeth help us to chew our food. They also help us to look nice. How does a tooth go bad? The decay begins in a little crack in the enamel covering the tooth. This happens after germs and bits of food have collected there. Then the decay slowly spreads inside the tooth. Eventually, poison goes into the blood, and we may feel quite ill.","How can we keep our teeth healthy? Firstly, we ought to visit our dentist twice a year. He can fill the small holes in our teeth before they destroy the teeth. He can examine our teeth to check that they are growing in the right way. Unfortunately, many people wait until they have a toothache before they see a dentist. Secondly, we should brush our teeth with a toothbrush and fluoride toothpaste at least twice a day - once after breakfast and once before we go to bed. We can also use wooden toothpicks to clean between our teeth after a meal. Thirdly, we should eat food that is good for our teeth and our body: milk, cheese, fish, brown bread, potatoes, red rice, raw vegetables, and fresh fruit. Chocolates, sweets, biscuits, and cakes are bad, especially when we eat them between meals. They are harmful because they stick to our teeth and cause decay."],"questions":[{"question":"When there is a little crack in the enamel covering the tooth, our teeth ___","A":"become hard","B":"make us feel quite good","C":"begin to decay","D":"become healthy","answer":"begin to decay"},{"question":"What does the word \'spreads\' mean?","A":"grows","B":"reduces","C":"sends","D":"collects","answer":"grows"},{"question":"What does the word \'Eventually\u201d mean?","A":"Firstly","B":"Slowly","C":"Lastly","D":"Moreover","answer":"Lastly"},{"question":"How often should we visit the dentist?","A":"twice a month","B":"twice a week","C":"twice a year","D":"every year","answer":"twice a year"},{"question":"A lot of people do not visit a dentist until______","A":"they have a toothache","B":"they use wooden toothpicks","C":"they have brushed their teeth","D":"their teeth grow properly","answer":"they have a toothache"},{"question":"When do we need to brush the teeth?","A":"Before the breakfast and after the meal","B":"Before breakfast and before the meal","C":"After the breakfast and before going to bed","D":"Before the meals and before going to bed","answer":"After the breakfast and before going to bed"},{"question":"What does the word \'wooden\' mean?","A":"made of wood","B":"made of steel","C":"made of iron","D":"made of nylon","answer":"made of wood"},{"question":"What may be beneficial to our teeth?","A":"Ice-cream","B":"vegetables and fruits","C":"caffeine","D":"tea","answer":"vegetables and fruits"},{"question":"What may be most harmful to our teeth?","A":"red rice","B":"raw vegetables","C":"fresh fruit","D":"sweet things","answer":"sweet things"},{"question":"How many pieces of advice are there to keep our teeth healthy","A":"1","B":"2","C":"3","D":"4","answer":"3"},{"question":"The best title for the passage would be_____","A":"How to keep our teeth healthy","B":"How to make our teeth nicer","C":"How to dean our teeth","D":"How to keep our teeth ever white","answer":"How to keep our teeth healthy"}]},{"passage":["Christopher Columbus was born in Genoa, Italy in 1451. While spending most of his early years at sea, Columbus began to believe that he could find a shortcut to the Indies by sailing west across the Atlantic Ocean. Unfortunately, the King of Portugal refused to finance such a trip, and Columbus was forced to present his idea to the King and Queen of Spain. In 1492, King Ferdinand and Queen Isabella agreed to pay for his trip. They gave him a crew and three ships, the Nina, Pinta and Santa Maria. Columbus sailed aboard the Santa Maria.","The trip was long and hard. Many sailors grew restless and wanted to turn around. After two months at sea, land was finally sighted. The ships docked on the island of Hispaniola. Columbus named the native people he saw \'Indians\', because he believed he had found the shortcut he was looking for. In reality, Columbus found North America, a brand new continent at that time.","Columbus, however, couldn\u2019t be convinced. He died with the belief he had found the shortcut to the Indies. Soon, however, other explorers and nations understood the importance of his discoveries, Columbus\' discoveries set the stage for the Age of Exploration, one of the most fascinating and exciting times in the world history."],"questions":[{"question":"Where was Christopher Columbus born?","A":"The New World","B":"Portugal","C":"Spain","D":"Italy","answer":"Italy"},{"question":"Columbus believed he could find a shortcut to the","A":"America","B":"Indies","C":"Spain","D":"Atlantic Ocean","answer":"Indies"},{"question":"What does the word \'shortcut\' mean?","A":"trip","B":"short way","C":"journey","D":"voyage","answer":"short way"},{"question":"What does the word \'finance\' mean?","A":"pay for","B":"agree","C":"share","D":"present","answer":"pay for"},{"question":"Columbus set sail","A":"In 1451","B":"In 1492","C":"Before 1451","D":"Before 1492","answer":"In 1492"},{"question":"What does the word \'crew\' mean?","A":"team","B":"alone","C":"money","D":"gun","answer":"team"},{"question":"Which of the following was NOT one of his ships?","A":"Nina","B":"Isabella","C":"Pinta","D":"Santa Maria","answer":"Isabella"},{"question":"Which is NOT true?","A":"Columbus was born in Italy","B":"Columbus received three ships and a crew from the King and Queen of Spain.","C":"Columbus found a shortcut to the Indies","D":"The journey across the Atlantic took two months.","answer":"Columbus found a shortcut to the Indies"},{"question":"What does the word \'restless\' mean?","A":"without resting","B":"without working","C":"without eating","D":"without sailing","answer":"without resting"},{"question":"What does the word \'reality\' mean?","A":"though","B":"tum","C":"order","D":"fact","answer":"fact"},{"question":"What did Columbus name the native people he saw?","A":"King Ferdinand","B":"Queen Isabella","C":"Christopher Columbus","D":"The Indians","answer":"Christopher Columbus"},{"question":"What did Columbus name the native people he saw?","A":"Indies","B":"Indians","C":"Indi","D":"American","answer":"Indians"},{"question":"What did Columbus actually find?","A":"The Indies","B":"North America","C":"Atlantic Ocean","D":"Genoa","answer":"North America"}]},{"passage":["Green is a beautiful color in nature, the grass that you walk on is green and the leaves that you see on trees are usually green. Most of the plants that you see are green, too! Frogs are green and many grasshoppers are green, too. Turtles are different shades of green.","Did you know that you can make green paint with blue and yellow? Because you can make green by mixing two primary colors, it is called a secondary color. Green is also the name used to describe the movement to make products that do not harm the Earth. Green products are often those made from recycled materials or those that are safe to throw out in the trash."],"questions":[{"question":"Which of the following might be an example of a green product?","A":"a plastic bottle that can be recycled","B":"a big truck","C":"a frog","D":"a plastic bottle that cannot be recycled","answer":"a plastic bottle that can be recycled"},{"question":"Which of the following might not be an example of green in nature?","A":"the grass","B":"the plant","C":"the leaf","D":"the bike","answer":"the bike"},{"question":"According to the passage, which is NOT given as an example of green?","A":"A mushroom","B":"A frog","C":"A grasshopper","D":"A leaf","answer":"A mushroom"},{"question":"Turtles are___","A":"different shades of green","B":"green products","C":"not found in nature","D":"not green","answer":"different shades of green"},{"question":"Green paint can be created by mixing___","A":"yellow and red","B":"yellow and blue","C":"yellow and purple","D":"yellow and brown","answer":"yellow and blue"},{"question":"Green is called___ by mixing two primary colors.","A":"primary color","B":"a type of kite","C":"a secondary color","D":"a kind of trash","answer":"a secondary color"},{"question":"What does the word \'primary\' mean?","A":"new","B":"unimportant","C":"private","D":"basic","answer":"basic"},{"question":"What is the word \'movement\' closest in meaning to?","A":"journey","B":"trip","C":"visit","D":"action","answer":"action"},{"question":"What is a green product?","A":"One that does not harm the Earth","B":"One that is fun","C":"One that is mixed together","D":"One that is made from grass","answer":"One that does not harm the Earth"},{"question":"Which can be the best title for the passage?","A":"Green color","B":"Green animals","C":"Green plants","D":"the Earth","answer":"Green color"}]},{"passage":["Alexander Graham Bell was born in Edinburgh, Scotland on March 3, 1847. When he was only eleven years old, he invented a machine that could clean wheat. Graham studied anatomy and physiology at the University of London, but moved with his family to Quebec, Canada in 1870.","Bell soon moved to Boston, Massachusetts. In 1871, he began working with deaf people and published the system of Visible Hearing that was developed by his father. Visible Hearing illustrates how the tongue, lips, and throat are used to produce vocal sounds. In 1872, Bell founded a school for the deaf which soon became part of Boston University.","Alexander Graham Bell is best known for his invention of the telephone. While trying to discover the secret of transmitting multiple messages on a single wire, Bell heard the sound of a plucked string along some of the electrical wires. One of Bell\u2019s assistants, Thomas A. Watson, was trying to reactivate a telephone transmitter. After hearing the sound, Bell believed he could send the sound of a human voice over the wire. After receiving a patent on March 7, 1876 for transmitting sound along a single wire, he successfully transmitted human speech on March 10th. Bell\u2019s telephone patent was one of the most valuable patents ever granted. He started the Bell Telephone Company in 1877.","Alexander Graham Bell died on August 2, 1922. On the day of his burial, in honor of Bell, all telephone services in the United States were stopped for one minute."],"questions":[{"question":"Where was Alexander Graham Bell born?","A":"England","B":"Quebec","C":"Scotland","D":"Boston","answer":"Scotland"},{"question":"When did he invent the machine that could clean wheat?","A":"In 1947","B":"In 1958","C":"In 1870","D":"In 1871","answer":"In 1958"},{"question":"Who developed the system of Visible Hearing?","A":"Himself","B":"His workmate","C":"His father","D":"The deaf","answer":"His father"},{"question":"What does the word \'illustrates\' mean?","A":"describes","B":"draws","C":"moves","D":"listens","answer":"describes"},{"question":"What did Alexander Graham Bell do in 1872?","A":"He invented a machine for cleaning wheat.","B":"He founded a school for deaf people","C":"He invented the telephone","D":"He studied at the University of London","answer":"He founded a school for deaf people"},{"question":"What happened FIRST?","A":"Bell invented the telephone","B":"Bell moved to Canada","C":"Bell published the Visible Hearing system","D":"Bell moved to Massachusetts","answer":"Bell moved to Canada"},{"question":"Bell was most famous for the invention of_______","A":"photograph","B":"telephone","C":"wire","D":"electricity","answer":"telephone"},{"question":"Who was Thomas A. Watson?","A":"Bell\'s assistant","B":"Bell\'s cousin","C":"Bell\'s son","D":"Bell\'s friend","answer":"Bell\'s assistant"},{"question":"What was Thomas doing when Alexander heard the sound of a plucked string along some of the electrical wires?","A":"Transmitting multiple messages over a single wire","B":"Transmitting the human voice over a single wire","C":"Starting the Bell Telephone Company","D":"Reactivating a telephone transmitter","answer":"Reactivating a telephone transmitter"},{"question":"What does the word \'transmitted\' mean?","A":"blocked by stopping","B":"sent out","C":"made larger","D":"disturbed","answer":"sent out"},{"question":"What does the word \'granted\' mean?","A":"welcomed","B":"issued","C":"loved","D":"started","answer":"issued"},{"question":"What happened in 1877?","A":"He started the Bell Telephone Company","B":"He closed the Bell Telephone Company.","C":"He left the Bell Telephone Company.","D":"He hired the Bell Telephone Company.","answer":"He started the Bell Telephone Company"},{"question":"He died at the age of_____","A":"73","B":"75","C":"77","D":"79","answer":"75"},{"question":"What happened on the day of his burial?","A":"All telephone services in the world were stopped.","B":"All telephone services in the US were stopped for one hour.","C":"All telephone services in the world were stopped for sixty seconds.","D":"All telephone services in the US were stopped for sixty seconds","answer":"All telephone services in the US were stopped for sixty seconds"},{"question":"Which can be the best title for the passage?","A":"Alexander Graham Bell\'s life and inventions","B":"Alexander Graham Bell\'s inventions","C":"The best inventor of all time","D":"Alexander Graham Bell\'s experiments","answer":"Alexander Graham Bell\'s life and inventions"}]}]')},249:function(e,t,n){},264:function(e,t,n){"use strict";n.r(t);var a=n(0),o=n.n(a),s=n(30),i=n.n(s),r=n(1),h=n(8),d=n(17),l=n(19),u=n(22),c=n(21),w=n(267),m=n(271),g=n(64),f=n(168),p=n(268),y=n(269),b=n(272),v=(n(177),n(10)),_=n(270),A=_.a.Title,C=function(e){Object(u.a)(n,e);var t=Object(c.a)(n);function n(){var e;return Object(d.a)(this,n),(e=t.call(this)).onclick=function(t){null===e.state.text&&t===e.props.answer&&e.props.addScore(),e.setState({text:t})},e.state={text:null},e}return Object(l.a)(n,[{key:"componentDidMount",value:function(){this.setState({text:null})}},{key:"UNSAFE_componentWillReceiveProps",value:function(e){this.props.question!==e.question&&this.setState({text:null})}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this,t=this.props,n=t.question,a=t.A,o=t.B,s=t.C,i=t.D,r=t.answer,h=this.state.text;return Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{display:"flex",flexDirection:"column",background:"#FFF",padding:20,margin:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(A,{level:4,children:n}),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{marginTop:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&a!==r,onClick:function(){return e.onclick(a)},danger:h&&a===r,type:"primary",children:"A"}),Object(v.jsx)("span",{className:"left",children:a})]}),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{marginTop:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&o!==r,onClick:function(){return e.onclick(o)},danger:h&&o===r,type:"primary",children:"B"}),Object(v.jsx)("span",{className:"left",children:o})]}),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{marginTop:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&s!==r,onClick:function(){return e.onclick(s)},danger:h&&s===r,type:"primary",children:"C"}),Object(v.jsx)("span",{className:"left",children:s})]}),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{marginTop:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&i!==r,onClick:function(){return e.onclick(i)},danger:h&&i===r,type:"primary",children:"D"}),Object(v.jsx)("span",{className:"left",children:i})]})]})}}]),n}(a.Component),B=(n(249),_.a.Title),k=function(e){Object(u.a)(n,e);var t=Object(c.a)(n);function n(){var e;return Object(d.a)(this,n),(e=t.call(this)).onclick=function(t){t===e.props.answer&&e.props.addScore(),e.setState({text:t})},e.state={text:null},e}return Object(l.a)(n,[{key:"UNSAFE_componentWillReceiveProps",value:function(e){this.props.question!==e.question&&this.setState({text:null})}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this,t=this.props,n=t.question,a=t.A,o=t.B,s=t.C,i=t.D,r=t.answer,h=this.state.text,d=n;return d=(d=(d=(d=d.replace(new RegExp("\\b".concat(a,"\\b")),'<span class="underline">'.concat(a,"</span>"))).replace(new RegExp("\\b".concat(o,"\\b")),'<span class="underline">'.concat(o,"</span>"))).replace(new RegExp("\\b".concat(s,"\\b")),'<span class="underline">'.concat(s,"</span>"))).replace(new RegExp("\\b".concat(i,"\\b")),'<span class="underline">'.concat(i,"</span>")),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{className:"part2",style:{display:"flex",flexDirection:"column",background:"#FFF",padding:20,margin:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)(B,{level:4,children:Object(v.jsx)("div",{dangerouslySetInnerHTML:{__html:d}})}),Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{marginTop:10,display:"flex",justifyContent:"flex-start"},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&a!==r,onClick:function(){return e.onclick(a)},danger:h&&a===r,type:"primary",children:"A"}),Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&o!==r,style:{marginLeft:10},onClick:function(){return e.onclick(o)},danger:h&&o===r,type:"primary",children:"B"}),Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&s!==r,style:{marginLeft:10},onClick:function(){return e.onclick(s)},danger:h&&s===r,type:"primary",children:"C"}),Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{disabled:h&&i!==r,style:{marginLeft:10},onClick:function(){return e.onclick(i)},danger:h&&i===r,type:"primary",children:"D"})]})]})}}]),n}(a.Component),q=(_.a.Title,_.a.Paragraph),D=function(e){Object(u.a)(n,e);var t=Object(c.a)(n);function n(){var e;return Object(d.a)(this,n),(e=t.call(this)).onclick=function(t){var n="B\u1ea1n \u0111\xe3 l\xe0m sai c\xe2u h\u1ecfi n\xe0y, \u0111\u1ec1 ngh\u1ecb ch\u1ecdn c\xe2u kh\xe1c \u0111\u1ec3 ch\u1ecdn \u0111\u01b0\u1ee3c \u0111\xe1p \xe1n \u0111\xfang !^^";t===e.props.answer&&(e.setState({text:t}),n="Ch\xfac m\u1eebng b\u1ea1n \u0111\xe3 ch\u1ecdn \u0111\u01b0\u1ee3c \u0111\xe1p \xe1n ch\xednh x\xe1c !^^"),f.a.open({message:"Th\xf4ng b\xe1o",description:n})},e.state={text:"",questions:[]},e}return Object(l.a)(n,[{key:"componentDidMount",value:function(){var e=this.props.questions.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5}));this.setState({questions:e}),window.fontSize=18}},{key:"UNSAFE_componentWillReceiveProps",value:function(e){this.props.question!==e.question&&this.setState({text:null})}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this,t=this.props,n=t.passage,a=(t.A,t.B,t.C,t.D,this.state.questions);this.state.text;return Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{display:"flex",flexDirection:"column",background:"#FFF",padding:20,margin:10},children:[Object(v.jsx)("div",{style:{display:"flex",flexDirection:"column",background:"#FFF",padding:20,margin:10,position:"sticky",top:0,zIndex:999,fontSize:window.fontSize},children:n.map((function(e){return Object(v.jsx)(q,{children:e})}))}),a.map((function(t){return Object(v.jsx)(C,Object(r.a)({addScore:e.props.addScore},t))}))]})}}]),n}(a.Component),I=n(129),S=n(130),T=n(131),W=n(132),x=n(133),H=n(134),j=n(135),O=n(160),N=n(121),M=[I,S,T],E=[W,x,H],J=[j,N,O],P=[{name:"2021",part1:I,part2:W,part3:j,socre:0,highScore:0},{name:"2016",part1:S,part2:x,part3:N,socre:0,highScore:0},{name:"2005",part1:T,part2:H,part3:N,socre:0,highScore:0}],F=w.a.Content,U=m.a.Countdown,G=(Date.now(),function(e){Object(u.a)(n,e);var t=Object(c.a)(n);function n(){var e;return Object(d.a)(this,n),(e=t.call(this)).columns=[{title:"T\xean b\xe0i",dataIndex:"name",width:"30%",editable:!0},{title:"\u0110i\u1ec3m cao nh\u1ea5t",dataIndex:"highScore"},{title:"\u0110i\u1ec3m",dataIndex:"socre"},{title:"Ch\u1ee9c n\u0103ng",dataIndex:"operation",render:function(t,n){return Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{type:"primary",onClick:function(){return e.start(n)},children:"B\u1eaft \u0111\u1ea7u"})}}],e.handleAdd=function(){var t=e.state.dataSource,n=M.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5}))[0],a=E.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5}))[0],o=J.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5}))[0],s=n.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5})),i=a.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5})),r=o.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5})),d={name:"random test "+t.length,part1:s,part2:i,part3:r,socre:0,highScore:0},l=[].concat(Object(h.a)(t),[d]);e.setState({dataSource:l}),localStorage.setItem("randomTest",JSON.stringify(l))},e.onFinish=function(){f.a.open({message:"Th\xf4ng b\xe1o",description:"H\u1ebft th\u1eddi gian l\xe0m b\xe0i !^^"})},e.addScore=function(){var t=e.state.score;e.setState({score:t+1})},e.start=function(t){console.log(t),e.setState({loadding:!1,time:Date.now()+72e5,item:t,score:0})},e.end=function(){var t=e.state,n=t.item,a=t.dataSource,o=t.score,s=a.filter((function(e){return e.name===n.name}));o>s.highScore&&(s.highScore=o),s.score=o,e.setState({loadding:!0,dataSource:Array.from(a)})},e.state={score:0,loadding:!0,time:0,dataSource:[],randomTest:[],item:null},e}return Object(l.a)(n,[{key:"componentDidMount",value:function(){var e=localStorage.getItem("randomTest");e?this.setState({dataSource:JSON.parse(e)}):(localStorage.setItem("randomTest",JSON.stringify(P)),this.setState({dataSource:P}))}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this,t=this.state,n=t.score,a=t.loadding,o=t.time,s=t.dataSource,i=(t.randomTest,t.item);return a?Object(v.jsx)(w.a,{style:{height:"100vh",alignItems:"center",justifyContent:"center"},children:Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{width:1e3},children:[Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{onClick:this.handleAdd,type:"primary",style:{marginBottom:16},children:"Add a row"}),Object(v.jsx)(p.a,{bordered:!0,dataSource:s,columns:this.columns})]})}):Object(v.jsxs)(w.a,{style:{alignItems:"center"},children:[Object(v.jsxs)("div",{style:{position:"fixed",top:50,left:50},children:[Object(v.jsx)(y.a,{children:Object(v.jsx)(U,{title:"Th\u1eddi gian l\xe0m b\xe0i",value:o,onFinish:this.onFinish})}),Object(v.jsx)(y.a,{children:Object(v.jsx)(m.a,{title:"\u0110i\u1ec3m",value:n,prefix:Object(v.jsx)(b.a,{})})}),Object(v.jsx)(y.a,{children:Object(v.jsx)(g.a,{type:"primary",danger:!0,onClick:this.end,children:"N\u1ed9p b\xe0i"})})]}),Object(v.jsxs)(F,{style:{width:1e3},children:[Object(v.jsx)("h1",{children:"PH\u1ea6N 1: C\u1ea4U TR\xdaC VA\u0300 CA\u0301CH DI\xca\u0303N \u0110A\u0323T"}),Object(v.jsx)("h3",{children:"C\xc2U HO\u0309I 1-20: Cho\u0323n \u0111a\u0301p a\u0301n thi\u0301ch h\u01a1\u0323p (A, B, C ho\u0103\u0323c D) \u0111\xea\u0309 hoa\u0300n tha\u0300nh ca\u0301c c\xe2u sau."}),i.part1.map((function(t){return Object(v.jsx)(C,{addScore:e.addScore,question:t.question,A:t.A,B:t.B,C:t.C,D:t.D,answer:t.answer})})),Object(v.jsx)("h3",{children:"C\xc2U HO\u0309I 21-50: Cho\u0323n ph\xe2\u0300n ga\u0323ch ch\xe2n \u0111\u01b0\u01a1\u0323c \u0111a\u0301nh d\xe2\u0301u theo th\u01b0\u0301 t\u01b0\u0323 A, B, C va\u0300 D co\u0301 ch\u01b0\u0301a l\xf4\u0303i sai."}),i.part2.map((function(t){return Object(v.jsx)(k,Object(r.a)({addScore:e.addScore},t))})),Object(v.jsx)("h1",{children:"PH\u1ea6N 2: \u0110O\u0323C HI\xca\u0309U"}),Object(v.jsx)("h3",{children:"C\xc2U HO\u0309I 21-50: Cho\u0323n ph\xe2\u0300n ga\u0323ch ch\xe2n \u0111\u01b0\u01a1\u0323c \u0111a\u0301nh d\xe2\u0301u theo th\u01b0\u0301 t\u01b0\u0323 A, B, C va\u0300 D co\u0301 ch\u01b0\u0301a l\xf4\u0303i sai."}),i.part3.map((function(t){return Object(v.jsx)(D,Object(r.a)({addScore:e.addScore},t))}))]})]})}}]),n}(a.Component)),R=function(e){e&&e instanceof Function&&n.e(3).then(n.bind(null,273)).then((function(t){var n=t.getCLS,a=t.getFID,o=t.getFCP,s=t.getLCP,i=t.getTTFB;n(e),a(e),o(e),s(e),i(e)}))};i.a.render(Object(v.jsx)(o.a.StrictMode,{children:Object(v.jsx)(G,{})}),document.getElementById("root")),R()}},[[264,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.62f07836.chunk.js.map